<tool id="ls_align" name="LS align" version="@TOOL_VERSION@+galaxy@VERSION_SUFFIX@">
    <description>flexible ligand alignment</description>
    <macros>
        <token name="@TOOL_VERSION@">1.0</token>
        <token name="@VERSION_SUFFIX@">0</token>
    </macros>
    <requirements>
        <requirement type="package" version="2.4.1">openbabel</requirement>
    </requirements>
    <command ><![CDATA[
            cp '$test_mol' query.sdf &&
            cp '$target_mol' target.sdf &&
            cp '$__tool_directory__'/LSalign . &&
            cp '$__tool_directory__'/run.py . &&
            cp '$__tool_directory__'/run.sh . &&
            bash run.sh >> '$log_out' &&
            cp aligned.sdf '$sdf_out'
    ]]></command>
    <inputs>
       <param name="target_mol" type="data" format="sdf" label="Target"/>
       <param name="test_mol" type="data" format="sdf" label="Query molecule / database"/>
    </inputs>
    <outputs>
        <data name="log_out" format="txt"/>
        <data name="sdf_out" format="sdf"/>
    </outputs>
    <tests>
    </tests>
 <help><![CDATA[
        .. class:: infomark

        **What this tool does:**

        Determines the similarity between molecules based on their MAP4 fingerprints. The distance from the target is calculated, the clostest neighbour being the most similar molecule. Distances are calculated using a custom kernel/loss function suggested by the initial developers (see citation).

         .. class:: infomark

         **Inputs:**

         * Target - coordinate file as .mol2 (single molecule)

         * Query - coordinate file as .mol2 (single .mol2 file containing one or more molecules)


         .. class:: infomark


         **Outputs:**

         * A .sdf file containing the top hits as determined by the "Number of top hits to extract" field

         * A .csv file conatining the name of the Query molecule, and the calculated distance of the Query from target ranging from 0-1.

        .. class:: infomark

         **Note:**

* By default a 1024 bit hash with radius 2 is used to generate the MAP4 molecular fingerprint.

* Molecules should contain the correct bond orders and protonation states. Steroechemical information is not necessary as this information is removed in the process of calculating the MAP4 fingerprint.

* By default this tool submits jobs to a compute node which makes use of 16 cores and has a walltime of 72hrs.

    ]]></help>
    <citations>
    <citation type="bibtex">
@article{capecchi_one_2020,
        title = {One molecular fingerprint to rule them all: drugs, biomolecules, and the metabolome},
        volume = {12},
        issn = {1758-2946},
        shorttitle = {One molecular fingerprint to rule them all},
        url = {https://jcheminf.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s13321-020-00445-4},
        doi = {10.1186/s13321-020-00445-4},
}
</citation>
    </citations>
</tool>
